<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Users on Caleb Cushing&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.xenoterracide.com/tags/users/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Users on Caleb Cushing&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.xenoterracide.com/tags/users/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The real problem with windows is not windows</title>
      <link>http://blog.xenoterracide.com/post/the-real-problem-with-windows-is-not-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2008 12:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.xenoterracide.com/post/the-real-problem-with-windows-is-not-windows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(note: this was originally intended as a reply to &lt;a href=&#34;http://vivapinkfloyd.blogspot.com/2008/07/why-is-so-hard-for-windows-users-to.html&#34;&gt;Why Is So Hard for Windows Users to Understand That Linux Is Not Windows&lt;/a&gt;, but it got so long I felt it should be it&amp;rsquo;s own post. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure the title is good, but it&amp;rsquo;s close enough)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;(note: I use the term users in this blog to mean people who use computers that do not, develop, administrate, repair, or are other wise considered power users, and professional computer users.)&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t hate windows anymore, like &lt;a href=&#34;http://vivapinkfloyd.blogspot.com/2008/07/why-is-so-hard-for-windows-users-to.html&#34;&gt;Dan Craciun&lt;/a&gt; says they just aren&amp;rsquo;t the same thing. I switched to linux years ago, I see that it isn&amp;rsquo;t perfect anymore, but I still like it better than windows.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you told me that I had to ignore the constant rebooting on windows and the lack of gaming on linux. I would suggest that I can make either system as stable, and equal in terms of usefulness on the desktop. Sure it might take me a few more hours to secure windows, get drivers installed, and install security tools, and the software I like. But in the end they&amp;rsquo;d be close to the same, in usability and long term stability for me and normal users.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The truth? the problem with windows isn&amp;rsquo;t entirely windows&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s users. I could teach a user 99% of what they need to know to maintain their computer and keep it running smooth in an hour, but they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t listen, they&amp;rsquo;d continue to use IE to browse promiscuously, not keep their antivirus, antispyware that I installed up to date.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you were to change everyone running windows xp to ubuntu (I don&amp;rsquo;t like ubuntu btw) today, I predict in 6 months to a year ubuntu users would have as many problems as windows users today? why? they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t update there systems&amp;hellip; they&amp;rsquo;d disable their firewalls, they would browse to all sorts of bad sites that contain the new linux malware.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;How do I know this? I&amp;rsquo;ve put &amp;lsquo;users&amp;rsquo; on linux, specifically opensuse, which has a nice little update checker&amp;hellip; I show them how to use that after resolving the problems of codecs, and drivers and whatever else install problems they might have. In a week that icon is red, and will stay that way indefinitely because they never ever run updates.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So the real problem is users not treating there computers like cars, and ignoring the fact that they need proper maintenance and there are just some things you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t do with them. True linux is easier for me to fix, mostly due to the lack of a registry, but the  problem is not make and model, but lack of maintenance (and yes some makes and models are easier to maintain). If you don&amp;rsquo;t ever get an oil change or add to your oil your engine will burn up a lot faster than it would if you had take care of it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The one thing that M$ does that causes me to still hate them, because it affects me, is IE. If I had one thing I wanted from microsoft it would be a browser with the standards compliance on par with the likes of Mozilla Firefox (they don&amp;rsquo;t have to achieve opera, or webkit) and without their own proprietary syntax, they have to do it the same way as everyone else (e.g. no active X calls instead of XMLHttpRequest..) But even if IE8 managed to be this browser, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t help anytime soon&amp;hellip; why? because users don&amp;rsquo;t update their software.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;br /&gt;
This &lt;span xmlns:dc=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/&#34; href=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/dcmitype/Text&#34; rel=&#34;dc:type&#34;&gt;work&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a xmlns:cc=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/ns#&#34; href=&#34;http://www.xenoterracide.com&#34; property=&#34;cc:attributionName&#34; rel=&#34;cc:attributionURL&#34;&gt;Caleb Cushing&lt;/a&gt; is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>