<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spring Data on Caleb Cushing&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.xenoterracide.com/tags/spring-data/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spring Data on Caleb Cushing&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.xenoterracide.com/tags/spring-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Single Repository, one Aggregate</title>
      <link>http://blog.xenoterracide.com/post/single-repository-one-aggregate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.xenoterracide.com/post/single-repository-one-aggregate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.martinfowler.com/eaaCatalog/repository.html&#34;&gt;Repository&lt;/a&gt; as defined in &lt;a href=&#34;http://dddcommunity.org/book/evans_2003/&#34;&gt;Domain Driven Design&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;manages a single &lt;a href=&#34;http://martinfowler.com/bliki/DDD_Aggregate.html&#34;&gt;Aggregate&lt;/a&gt;. An aggregate may contain many entities, and value objects, but will have a single object as its root. Many of the Dao and even now some of the Repository implementations I see do not follow this, they are more likely to have a Repository per entity, than a Repository per aggregate, and of course in some cases this is required for various reasons.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ok, to start out we need our POM (or you can use Gradle), which configures our dependencies and plugins. We use a starter for Spring Data JPA, which pulls in Spring Data JPA and all of it&amp;rsquo;s suggested dependencies such as Hibernate. We also need a database and a database driver so we configure H2. Since we are inheriting from the Spring Platform BOM we don&amp;rsquo;t need to specify versions as it can configure them for us. We of course want to use Java 8 and specify our Application class so we will be able to run &lt;code&gt;mvn spring-boot:run&lt;/code&gt; at the end. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;https://bitbucket.org/xenoterracide/spring-data-aggregate-persist/src/15cb2c11f5f29d9ac6cee2bf33c984b2b857afea/pom.xml?embed=t&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Next Let&amp;rsquo;s configure our application to show the SQL that it is running, this isn&amp;rsquo;t required. You need to put &lt;code&gt;application.properties&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code&gt;src/main/resources&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;https://bitbucket.org/xenoterracide/spring-data-aggregate-persist/src/15cb2c11f5f29d9ac6cee2bf33c984b2b857afea/src/main/resources/application.properties?embed=t&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; Now we need to create our Entities, let&amp;rsquo;s start at the entity Bar that is the deepest part of the Aggregate root. It extends &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.spring.io/spring-data/jpa/docs/current/api/org/springframework/data/jpa/domain/AbstractPersistable.html&#34;&gt;AbstractPersistable&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;so that we get an Auto Incrementing or Sequenced id. We also use AbstractPeristable because for our task we require that our entities implement &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.spring.io/spring-data/data-commons/docs/current/api/org/springframework/data/domain/Persistable.html&#34;&gt;Persistable&lt;/a&gt;, as it changes the behavior of save on the repository if your objects are new.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;https://bitbucket.org/xenoterracide/spring-data-aggregate-persist/src/15cb2c11f5f29d9ac6cee2bf33c984b2b857afea/src/main/java/com/xenoterracide/Bar.java?embed=t&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;Next let&amp;rsquo;s create Foo, it is much the same, but you&amp;rsquo;ll notice the &lt;code&gt;@OneToOne&lt;/code&gt; that specifies &lt;code&gt;CascadeType.ALL&lt;/code&gt;. This is important as without it persist and merge won&amp;rsquo;t work.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;https://bitbucket.org/xenoterracide/spring-data-aggregate-persist/src/15cb2c11f5f29d9ac6cee2bf33c984b2b857afea/src/main/java/com/xenoterracide/Foo.java?embed=t&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; Alright, let&amp;rsquo;s put together our repository, we could just make a CrudRepository, but let&amp;rsquo;s show off some paging too. You&amp;rsquo;ll notice that you have to pass the Entity and it&amp;rsquo;s Primary Key identifier type to the PagingAndSorting interface, the single method that we specify will find all the Foos by the nested baz property, using a &lt;code&gt;LIKE &amp;lsquo;%mystring%&amp;rsquo;&lt;/code&gt; query. Spring data will parse this interface and make an implementation for you automatically.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;https://bitbucket.org/xenoterracide/spring-data-aggregate-persist/src/15cb2c11f5f29d9ac6cee2bf33c984b2b857afea/src/main/java/com/xenoterracide/FooRepo.java?embed=t&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; You can create other lastly we do our Application, which is not designed to be a web server (it will exit immediately). The &lt;code&gt;@SpringBootApplication&lt;/code&gt; makes Spring Boot able to start the app and scan for components appropriately. We also Enable JPA repositories using the &lt;code&gt;@EnableJpaRepositories&lt;/code&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s main method (not recommended to prepopulate data this way), creates and save several Foos with nested bars, then I demonstrate a way that you can page the saved objects 2 at a time whilst filtering by that like statement, only 3 of the 4 entities saved will return. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;https://bitbucket.org/xenoterracide/spring-data-aggregate-persist/src/15cb2c11f5f29d9ac6cee2bf33c984b2b857afea/src/main/java/com/xenoterracide/Application.java?embed=t&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://bitbucket.org/xenoterracide/spring-data-aggregate-persist&#34;&gt;The full source is available here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;br /&gt;
This &lt;span xmlns:dc=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/&#34; href=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/dcmitype/Text&#34; rel=&#34;dc:type&#34;&gt;work&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a xmlns:cc=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/ns#&#34; href=&#34;http://www.xenoterracide.com&#34; property=&#34;cc:attributionName&#34; rel=&#34;cc:attributionURL&#34;&gt;Caleb Cushing&lt;/a&gt; is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>