<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cell Provider on Caleb Cushing&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.xenoterracide.com/tags/cell-provider/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cell Provider on Caleb Cushing&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.xenoterracide.com/tags/cell-provider/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Bad Customer Service from T-Mobile</title>
      <link>http://blog.xenoterracide.com/post/bad-customer-service-from-t-mobile/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2010 12:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.xenoterracide.com/post/bad-customer-service-from-t-mobile/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So about 2 months ago I got fed up with Sprint (they suck for different reasons) and I already knew that they had better service coverage than Verizon in my area. My friend suggested T-Mobile, so I went and got setup with them for a 14 day trial period. I took the phone made some calls tried the web browser, I didn&amp;rsquo;t like the blackberry itself, but that&amp;rsquo;s besides the point. When I got the phone home, no service, not even outside the house, making T-Mobile worse than Verizon. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to run 10 miles into town that day, the next day we had a blizzard, so wednesday, two days later I took it back. They charged back everything and everything seemed good. Until a few weeks later when I got a $10 bill for usage. I just finally got around to dealing with customer service today. They say it&amp;rsquo;s accurate, and no they can&amp;rsquo;t do anything. So basically as an FYI to anyone else, don&amp;rsquo;t try T-Mobile unless you already know that their service will work for you because they are going to charge you anyways. This shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be, your service doesn&amp;rsquo;t work for me, you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t charge me to tell you that. Now if I move I probably won&amp;rsquo;t look at them for a service change, had they handled this in an amicable manner I probably would have as soon as there network wasn&amp;rsquo;t an issue. I&amp;rsquo;m also going to tell anyone who asks about cell provider&amp;rsquo;s about it. Yes $10 isn&amp;rsquo;t much, but it&amp;rsquo;s the principle of me having to pay them anything after I had made it clear I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure it would work and I just wanted to see if it was an option.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;br /&gt;
This &lt;span xmlns:dc=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/&#34; href=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/dcmitype/Text&#34; rel=&#34;dc:type&#34;&gt;work&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a xmlns:cc=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/ns#&#34; href=&#34;http://www.xenoterracide.com&#34; property=&#34;cc:attributionName&#34; rel=&#34;cc:attributionURL&#34;&gt;Caleb Cushing&lt;/a&gt; is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>