<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community on Caleb Cushing&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.xenoterracide.com/tags/community/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Community on Caleb Cushing&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.xenoterracide.com/tags/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu isn&#39;t Linux, What&#39;s a Beginner anyways?</title>
      <link>http://blog.xenoterracide.com/post/ubuntu-isnt-linux-whats-a-beginner-anyways/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2010 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.xenoterracide.com/post/ubuntu-isnt-linux-whats-a-beginner-anyways/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today Joel Spolsky &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.stackoverflow.com/2010/09/fork-it/&#34;&gt;announced The results&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.stackoverflow.com/2010/08/should-unix-linux-and-ubuntu-be-merged-vote/&#34;&gt;the poll&lt;/a&gt; of whether &lt;a href=&#34;http://ubuntu.stackexchange.com/&#34;&gt;ubuntu SE&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://unix.stackexchange.com/&#34;&gt;unix SE&lt;/a&gt; would be merged, they won&amp;rsquo;t. In short the Unix community was in favor of it but the Ubuntu community was not. Joel had this to say: &lt;blockquote&gt;So, Ubuntu, Linux, I get it, it’s clearly not the same thing. If you love Ubuntu, we have a site for you. If you love Linux and Unix, we have a site for you. A Stack Exchange can’t work without a community that loves a subject, and love is very… specific. Fighting human nature is hard: the factionalism and fork-happiness of the Unix world has been a hallmark of that community ever since BSD vs. System V, and Stack Exchange can no more bridge that gap than we can unite the Judean resistance.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I am horribly disappointed in this decision, this factionalism doesn&amp;rsquo;t help the cause, this set&amp;rsquo;s precedence that it&amp;rsquo;s ok in the StackExchange community to be a separatist. Arch Linux&amp;rsquo;s bash must not be the same as Ubuntu&amp;rsquo;s or Fedora&amp;rsquo;s, and of course they&amp;rsquo;ve made so many changes to upstream Gnome as to be unrecognizable as such.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The main argument in favor of this separatist movement is that Ubuntu is for beginners, if that&amp;rsquo;s so then why isn&amp;rsquo;t it beginner.unix SE? What&amp;rsquo;s a beginner anyways?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d dare wager that 99.999% (POOMA) of all Linux users are windows Power users, veterans, and refugees. So what&amp;rsquo;s a beginner? someone that doesn&amp;rsquo;t know what Firefox is? No they probably do. Maybe they don&amp;rsquo;t know where it is in the menu? I can see that&amp;hellip; but I don&amp;rsquo;t see how that can&amp;rsquo;t be answered with a Screenshot and a Ubuntu tag on Unix SE. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s someone who doesn&amp;rsquo;t know how to use the CLI? Well where do you define beginner from advanced? I realize someone reading there first shell programming Tut/Book/etc is a beginner, but are they no longer a beginner after that? how do you know you&amp;rsquo;re not a beginner anymore? When you choose to move beyond Ubuntu? If I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Linux for 5 years and I choose to move to FreeBSD am I a Beginner?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Why is that the answer to a beginner from an advanced user isn&amp;rsquo;t welcome? Is it good that beginner are exclusively answering other beginner questions?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In other news it looks like I may become a moderator ( temporary at least ) for unix SE.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;br /&gt;
This &lt;span xmlns:dc=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/&#34; href=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/dcmitype/Text&#34; rel=&#34;dc:type&#34;&gt;work&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a xmlns:cc=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/ns#&#34; href=&#34;http://www.xenoterracide.com&#34; property=&#34;cc:attributionName&#34; rel=&#34;cc:attributionURL&#34;&gt;Caleb Cushing&lt;/a&gt; is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If you can&#39;t beat them, join them</title>
      <link>http://blog.xenoterracide.com/post/if-you-cant-beat-them-join-them/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2010 12:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.xenoterracide.com/post/if-you-cant-beat-them-join-them/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been heavily criticized for criticizing, critiquing, and complaining about lack of quality in open source projects. I have done these things because I care, generally because I care about that specific project, or Open Source (or whatever I&amp;rsquo;m talking about) in general. I&amp;rsquo;ve been attacked, insulted, and sworn at. I&amp;rsquo;ve recently come to the realization that the community support that behavior, to the point that they won&amp;rsquo;t stand up against those doing it. It is a very cliquish &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.markshuttleworth.com/archives/439&#34;&gt;and tribal&lt;/a&gt; community, if you&amp;rsquo;re in the &lt;em&gt;in&lt;/em&gt; crowd you can do or say what you want, if not you&amp;rsquo;ll be ostracized. I have been ostracized for years. I have decided to join the opinions of those I&amp;rsquo;ve been ostracized by, but also to accept my exile.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In order to discontinue my negative and inappropriate behavior, I have to stop caring. I choose now to not care about helping others who cannot (or choose not?) to help themselves. I will no longer complain about the problems of some projects, even those that I can and have provided fixes to the problems for. I will no longer fix problems that do not impact me. I will no longer tell people that they are misguided, no matter how much they are. I will no longer produce anything that doesn&amp;rsquo;t help me. I have to become selfish and stop caring about the problems of others.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To this end I&amp;rsquo;m discontinuing my &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/xenoterracide/AURpan&#34;&gt;work&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://aur.archlinux.org/&#34;&gt;Arch Linux&amp;rsquo;s AUR&lt;/a&gt; as it doesn&amp;rsquo;t help me, CPANPLUS::Dist::Arch which does most of the work, is more than capable of doing this for anyone using Arch, the packages will be orphaned. In acceptance of my exile I am removing myself from all IRC channels (though I will continue to connect) unless I have a problem, that way I do not end up causing a problem, it seems even when I have a problem and try to limit it to that I end up causing one. I am going to ask that my blog be removed from the Iron Man &amp;lsquo;competition&amp;rsquo;. I&amp;rsquo;ve been told that none of the work I&amp;rsquo;ve done is significant anyways, and thus my loss will not be a loss at all.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I will continue working on any project that has some benefit to myself, as my time is precious and I have a life outside of Open Source. I will only do so, however, if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t require me to have an opinion. There is no point in pushing for a fix that I have a workaround for already, I will simply be seen as entitled and asking too much of other peoples time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t win the fight by writing patches, or by helping people by answering questions, or sharing my knowledge publicly. So I choose not to fight, I choose to accept that I am not wanted and so I will leave.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;br /&gt;
This &lt;span xmlns:dc=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/&#34; href=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/dcmitype/Text&#34; rel=&#34;dc:type&#34;&gt;work&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a xmlns:cc=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/ns#&#34; href=&#34;http://www.xenoterracide.com&#34; property=&#34;cc:attributionName&#34; rel=&#34;cc:attributionURL&#34;&gt;Caleb Cushing&lt;/a&gt; is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>