<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Paludis on Caleb Cushing&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.xenoterracide.com/tags/paludis/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Paludis on Caleb Cushing&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.xenoterracide.com/tags/paludis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>pkgcore the victor</title>
      <link>http://blog.xenoterracide.com/post/pkgcore-the-victor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2008 01:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.xenoterracide.com/post/pkgcore-the-victor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;pkgcore is my pick for the next portage and codebase for emerge-ng. I admit I haven&amp;rsquo;t let paludis have a chance (yet).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why haven&amp;rsquo;t I let paludis have it&amp;rsquo;s chance?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The reasons are quite simple. Everytime I have tried paludis prior to this it has required extra configuration (meaning it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work out of the box). I believe this was fixed recently. However,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;code&gt;paludis@1208029212: [WARNING] Use of Portage configuration files will lead to sub-optimal performance and loss of functionality. Full support for Portage configuration formats is not guaranteed; issues should be reported via trac. You are strongly encouraged to migrate to a Paludis configuration.&lt;br /&gt;paludis@1208029212: [WARNING] Use of Portage configuration files will lead to sub-optimal performance and loss of functionality. Full support for Portage configuration formats is not guaranteed; issues should be reported via trac. You are strongly encouraged to migrate to a Paludis configuration.&lt;br /&gt;* Done cleaning write cache for ebuild format repositories&lt;br /&gt;paludis@1208029212: [WARNING] Use of Portage configuration files will lead to sub-optimal performance and loss of functionality. Full support for Portage configuration formats is not guaranteed; issues should be reported via trac. You are strongly encouraged to migrate to a Paludis configuration.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is the end of a paludis &amp;ndash;sync. Annoying. Paludis also has it&amp;rsquo;s alpha releases marked as  ~arch, this is a no, no. I also found the people in #paludis on irc to be rude and unhelpful. I was annoyed at the time (so being rude myself) as gentoo kde-svn overlay was going to require paludis which means I was going to be forced to use it. Regardless I&amp;rsquo;ve never been met with lot&amp;rsquo;s of friendliness or help in #paludis. They are an RTFM crowd. I have been told to use paludis several times without even asking about it (as if it is the solution to all problems). So is pkgcore better? I can&amp;rsquo;t say without a doubt that it is.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why is pkgcore the victor?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For starter&amp;rsquo;s it&amp;rsquo;s only the victor for me. paludis is a more mature product at this point and has a stronger following of fanatic&amp;rsquo;s/zealot&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;1.) pkgcore it more similar to portage.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;pkgcore was originally intended to be portage 3. This leads to a large amount of similarities and backwards compatibility.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;2.) pkgcore devs are really friendly. Sometimes patience is a virtue getting an answer on #pkgcore but most of the times I get one. This allowed me to quickly learn what I could and could not (yet) do with pkgcore, including finding a bug within a week.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;3.) pkgcore just works. I installed pkgcore and with a quick look at the site was quickly able to start doing work with it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;4.) pkgcore installs faster. I think it took like an hour to build paludis on this machine (maybe more) pkgcore took 2 minutes tops.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;5.) pkgcore uses C. For the parts of portage that were really slow they re-wrote them in C using cpython. using both python and c leads to faster development and speed where needed.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do I use pkgcore&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;real quick&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;code&gt;pmaint sync&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;this is the biggest adaption from portage, imho and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why it&amp;rsquo;s not &amp;ndash;sync or pmerge &amp;ndash;sync (in some ways it&amp;rsquo;s more similar to portage 2.0 syntax). This will not only sync your main gentoo tree but any repositories you&amp;rsquo;ve intalled with layman. as of yet you still have to install them via layman, but this may change in the future.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;code&gt;pmerge packagename&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I told you this was easy. Most of the options I use work. The biggest that doesn&amp;rsquo;t is &amp;ndash;verbose, this seems to be default now (with &amp;ndash;ask) so an option is no longer needed. updating world&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;code&gt;pmerge -auDs world&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;an -s is now needed to work with things like system and  world. It&amp;rsquo;s for package set. My one complaint here is the &amp;ndash;newuse doesn&amp;rsquo;t currently work with sets. This is a bug and will be fixed in the future.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; wrong with pkgcore in your eyes?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;well aside from the plethora of missing features (they&amp;rsquo;ll get done, it&amp;rsquo;s just a time thing). Documentation&amp;hellip; I usually learn stuff by reading web documentation (or books) until I&amp;rsquo;m comfortable enough reading man pages. The web documentation for pkgcore needs a lot of work. I may actually volunteer to help with this. I haven&amp;rsquo;t decided yet, and it depends partially on if they want to answer all my questions as I write the docs.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It&amp;rsquo;d be nice if at some point pmerge could become emerge etc&amp;hellip; (meaning reprise it&amp;rsquo;s roll as portage 3).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;for more information on pkgcore go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pkgcore.org/trac/pkgcore&#34;&gt;pkgcore.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;br /&gt;
This &lt;span xmlns:dc=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/&#34; href=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/dcmitype/Text&#34; rel=&#34;dc:type&#34;&gt;work&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a xmlns:cc=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/ns#&#34; href=&#34;http://www.xenoterracide.com&#34; property=&#34;cc:attributionName&#34; rel=&#34;cc:attributionURL&#34;&gt;Caleb Cushing&lt;/a&gt; is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>kde-overlay (svn) now requires paludis</title>
      <link>http://blog.xenoterracide.com/post/kde-overlay-svn-now-requires-paludis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2008 17:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.xenoterracide.com/post/kde-overlay-svn-now-requires-paludis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://article.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/55315&#34;&gt;details are here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;so apparently the folks running the kde overlay have decided to discontinue portage compatibility. I suppose I can&amp;rsquo;t blame them, on the other hand I don&amp;rsquo;t approve. Even though I haven&amp;rsquo;t started testing paludis yet. I am still firmly against it as it is as gentoo&amp;rsquo;s next package manager. I won&amp;rsquo;t be regen2&amp;rsquo;s without heavy modification. Including some re-writes. I do intend to investigate the possibility of using paludis code in emerge-ng.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;br /&gt;
This &lt;span xmlns:dc=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/&#34; href=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/dcmitype/Text&#34; rel=&#34;dc:type&#34;&gt;work&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a xmlns:cc=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/ns#&#34; href=&#34;http://www.xenoterracide.com&#34; property=&#34;cc:attributionName&#34; rel=&#34;cc:attributionURL&#34;&gt;Caleb Cushing&lt;/a&gt; is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>