<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Versions on Caleb Cushing&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.xenoterracide.com/tags/versions/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Versions on Caleb Cushing&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.xenoterracide.com/tags/versions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Semver.org probably not compat with all downstream</title>
      <link>http://blog.xenoterracide.com/post/semver.org-probably-not-compat-with-all-downstream/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2010 17:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.xenoterracide.com/post/semver.org-probably-not-compat-with-all-downstream/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For those that don&amp;rsquo;t know I currently create packages for &lt;a href=&#34;http://aur.archlinux.org/packages.php?SeB=m&amp;L=2&amp;K=xenoterracide&#34;&gt;AUR&lt;/a&gt;, and I used to work on &lt;a href=&#34;http://funtoo.org/&#34;&gt;Funtoo&lt;/a&gt;, as well as a fork of it Regen2 (which died by my hand). So I&amp;rsquo;ve got some experience working with BSD-ish style distro&amp;rsquo;s. I can&amp;rsquo;t comment on the Debians or Red Hats of the world, other than REPO HELL DRIVES ME NUTS. Now to the topic. &lt;a href=&#34;http://semver.org/&#34;&gt;Semver&lt;/a&gt; seems sane except for 1 thing that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t mention and an example that encourages it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;A normal version number MUST take the form X.Y.Z where X, Y, and Z are integers. X is the major version, Y is the minor version, and Z is the patch version. Each element MUST increase numerically. For instance: 1.9.0 &amp;lt; 1.10.0 &amp;lt; 1.11.0.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Not all packaging systems are capable of dealing with multipart as actual multiple parts. Lets give a more complete example to break it down. For instance: &lt;code&gt;1.9.0 &amp;lt; 1.10.0 &amp;lt; 1.11.0 &amp;lt; 2.0.0&lt;/code&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s what&amp;rsquo;s supposed to happen&amp;hellip; but that&amp;rsquo;s not how it works. Arch for example see&amp;rsquo;s versions as strings&amp;hellip; so let me show you what happens.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;pre&gt;190&lt;br /&gt;1100&lt;br /&gt;1110&lt;br /&gt;200&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is essentially what you could interpret the &amp;ldquo;.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rsquo;s are essentially ignored ( Ok it&amp;rsquo;s not actually how it works&amp;hellip; juster&amp;rsquo;s comment is more accurate than me but I think it&amp;rsquo;s a good rule of thumb). They don&amp;rsquo;t matter they&amp;rsquo;re like spaces between words, they simply make it easier for a human to read. Never ever, &lt;em&gt;ever&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVER!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; change the length of your versions to anything BUT larger. You will cause downstream annoyances, sure we&amp;rsquo;ve tools to work around it, but I don&amp;rsquo;t want to and it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t take any extra effort from upstream to make sure this doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In order to solve this if you ever need to move anything to double digits just don&amp;rsquo;t go backwards. In other words: &lt;code&gt;1.9.0 &amp;lt; 1.10.0 &amp;lt; 1.11.0 &amp;lt; 2.00.0&lt;/code&gt; would actually evaluate properly. I find it more likely that in an X.Y.Z schema that you will need X.Y.ZZ though, and maybe X.YY.ZZ. For a project More than 10 years old XX.YY.ZZ could happen. Anything more is probably ridiculous. If you find yourself hitting 99 slow your roll before you reach it by moving to a time based release, no more than once a month for example.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Some people will say that Arch doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a sane internal representation. Keep in mind that maintain over 300 package now for arch&amp;hellip; of those 300 maybe 10 have ever caused me to create a workaround because of this issue. It&amp;rsquo;s not difficult, so please just be considerate of downstream, it&amp;rsquo;s a lot easier to acknowledge and be mindful of this than it is to fix downstream in a way that would work for all upstream packages (e.g. we&amp;rsquo;ve got more to consider that just your package).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;UPDATE: Read juster&amp;rsquo;s comment if you want more information on actual implementation and how I&amp;rsquo;m slightly wrong.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;br /&gt;
This &lt;span xmlns:dc=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/&#34; href=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/dcmitype/Text&#34; rel=&#34;dc:type&#34;&gt;work&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a xmlns:cc=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/ns#&#34; href=&#34;http://www.xenoterracide.com&#34; property=&#34;cc:attributionName&#34; rel=&#34;cc:attributionURL&#34;&gt;Caleb Cushing&lt;/a&gt; is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regen2 0.9.1.0 soon</title>
      <link>http://blog.xenoterracide.com/post/regen2-0.9.1.0-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2009 02:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.xenoterracide.com/post/regen2-0.9.1.0-soon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night I decided I&amp;rsquo;d be rolling out the first release of Regen2 in the first week of April.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So as I&amp;rsquo;m sure everyone knows version are arbitrary they mean nothing&amp;hellip; well ours are going to mean something. The first 2 numbers are the year, so 20(0.9).1.0. the Third number is the quarter, we are going to be mass stabilizing system once per quarter. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that this will include new profiles. 4rth number is kinda arbitrary at this point, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how/if I want to use it, opinions welcome. since releases will be &amp;lsquo;stable&amp;rsquo; I could use 0 as kind of an alpha, first release. 1 as beta, 2 as rc, and 3 as final. I could also do a 0-alpha1, 0-beta1, etc. and when stage4&amp;rsquo;s and other stuff are rolled out use the version number to denote updated non-system software. In other words I could do releases each month of say kde in stage4&amp;rsquo;s but I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t change system more than once a quarter.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So far my list of packages that&amp;rsquo;ll be marked stable include.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;gcc-4.3.3(maybe r1)&lt;br /&gt;glibc-2.9_20081201-r2&lt;br /&gt;openrc-0.4.3-r1&lt;br /&gt;baselayout-2.0.0-r2&lt;br /&gt;git-1.6.2.1&lt;br /&gt;perl-5.10.0&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll have to spend the next few days figuring out the rest.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m debating also on whether I&amp;rsquo;m locking down major or minor versions. meaning I might consider stabilizing gcc-4.3.4 in the middle of this quarter but not gcc-4.4.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m open to opinions on anything. This may be a dictatorship, but I still don&amp;rsquo;t mind hearing from people not me, as with enough eyes all bugs are shallow.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;br /&gt;
This &lt;span xmlns:dc=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/&#34; href=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/dcmitype/Text&#34; rel=&#34;dc:type&#34;&gt;work&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a xmlns:cc=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/ns#&#34; href=&#34;http://www.xenoterracide.com&#34; property=&#34;cc:attributionName&#34; rel=&#34;cc:attributionURL&#34;&gt;Caleb Cushing&lt;/a&gt; is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>