<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sql on Caleb Cushing&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.xenoterracide.com/tags/sql/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sql on Caleb Cushing&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.xenoterracide.com/tags/sql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How not to ask for help</title>
      <link>http://blog.xenoterracide.com/post/how-not-to-ask-for-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 00:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.xenoterracide.com/post/how-not-to-ask-for-help/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the story of my friends problem today.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;I got one for ya.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Field like field &lt;cite&gt;&amp;ndash;friend&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;so of course I&amp;rsquo;m like: &lt;quote&gt;? is that a question?&lt;/quote&gt; he had given me no prelude, no premise. response&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;I tried field like &amp;lsquo;%&amp;rsquo; + field2 + &amp;lsquo;%&amp;rsquo;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;No good though&lt;br /&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&amp;ndash;friend&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So I explained that % is a wildcard. He still hadn&amp;rsquo;t explained what his problem is or what he was trying to do.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;it giving you a syntax error? &lt;cite&gt;&amp;ndash;me&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So here I am trying to guess at what his problem is. I&amp;rsquo;ve never used sql server but a quick glance at postgres docs suggested the syntax was wrong. I know don&amp;rsquo;t query other docs than the software being used&amp;hellip; but I wanted to run a test locally to see if I could figure out what he was doing. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t work &lt;cite&gt;&amp;ndash;friend&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Oh! that&amp;rsquo;s very helpful&amp;hellip; way to give more information. I think I now know why he never asks questions in IRC or forums. He never learned how to ask a question and they won&amp;rsquo;t put up with him.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;so it&amp;rsquo;s not a syntax error it just doesn&amp;rsquo;t do what you want? &lt;cite&gt;&amp;ndash;me&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Right. The like command isn&amp;rsquo;t finding it &lt;cite&gt;&amp;ndash;friend&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So finally I&amp;rsquo;m able to determine&amp;hellip; his problem is he&amp;rsquo;s got a &lt;code&gt;&amp;hellip; WHERE &amp;hellip; LIKE &amp;hellip; &lt;/code&gt; that isn&amp;rsquo;t returning what he expects. This is still completely worthless because I still haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to figure out what he&amp;rsquo;s trying to do&amp;hellip; or more correctly I have but not why it isn&amp;rsquo;t working because his code is right. which means he&amp;rsquo;s fallen prey to the assumption that he knows what I need to know to solve his problem. He hadn&amp;rsquo;t given me enough info. After I tried to explain to him how to do what I thought he was trying to do and giving him a sample query and some data&amp;hellip; he gives me this&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Field1 = &amp;ldquo;4369&amp;rdquo;   field2 = &amp;ldquo;4311&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;4369&amp;rdquo; &lt;cite&gt;&amp;ndash;friend&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Now anyone who&amp;rsquo;s familiar with sets will probably realize the notation here is bad and so you can&amp;rsquo;t tell if these are sample columns or records. a more proper way to write this would have been &lt;code&gt;field1 = { &amp;lsquo;&amp;ldquo;4369&amp;rdquo;&amp;rsquo;} field2 = {&amp;lsquo;&amp;ldquo;4311&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;4369&amp;rdquo;&amp;rsquo;}&lt;/code&gt; I probably still would have been a little confused just because I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been sure he was writing it right. See the problem here is that field 2 is an array and therefore not stored properly in a relational manner, it&amp;rsquo;s why he has to do a much slower LIKE in the first place. After bantering to figure out that this was in fact text data these were single records I eventually figured out that what he was trying to do was find field2 if it contaned field1. However, his code was asking for field1 if it contained field2. basically he had his parameters reversed.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It took me 20 minutes of getting that data to realize they were reversed, which is shameful for me&amp;hellip; but I was trying to figure out things like VARCHAR or INTEGER&amp;hellip; he of course said it&amp;rsquo;s not an array, and I suppose it&amp;rsquo;s not an ARRAY type in sql.. but I guarantee that&amp;rsquo;s why it looks like that&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s really a foreign key stored as an array in a varchar. After I told him he lied and said it didn&amp;rsquo;t work only to come back 10 minutes later and say&amp;hellip; you were right.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;so the final should have been&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;code&gt;WHERE field2 LIKE &amp;lsquo;%&amp;rsquo; + field1 + &amp;lsquo;%&amp;rsquo;&lt;/code&gt; or in postgres &lt;code&gt;WHERE field2 LIKE &amp;lsquo;%&amp;rsquo; || field1 || &amp;lsquo;%&amp;rsquo;&lt;/code&gt; because we use the standard || for string concatenation instead of the +&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;br /&gt;
This &lt;span xmlns:dc=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/&#34; href=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/dcmitype/Text&#34; rel=&#34;dc:type&#34;&gt;work&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a xmlns:cc=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/ns#&#34; href=&#34;http://www.xenoterracide.com&#34; property=&#34;cc:attributionName&#34; rel=&#34;cc:attributionURL&#34;&gt;Caleb Cushing&lt;/a&gt; is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>empty() function for postgresql in sql</title>
      <link>http://blog.xenoterracide.com/post/empty-function-for-postgresql-in-sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2010 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.xenoterracide.com/post/empty-function-for-postgresql-in-sql/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In PostgreSQL the ASCII NULL or empty string &lt;code&gt;\0&lt;/code&gt; is seen as NOT NULL. This is because postgres developers consider any characters data. I know there are better discussions on it but I can&amp;rsquo;t find them right now. Unfortunately the programming language you are using probably doesn&amp;rsquo;t see it the same way. There&amp;rsquo;s a good chance that initialized variables are set to &lt;code&gt;\0&lt;/code&gt; and so when you try to insert from your language to a NOT NULL field with variables that are seen as undefined in your language, postgres accepts it, and now you have fields that you probably consider to have no data but are NOT NULL.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My function possibly would be better called empty_or_whitespace but in my mind any text field that contains only whitespace is empty, and I&amp;rsquo;d rather have 1 function and 1 regex deal with both than have 2 functions have to be called on every insert/update.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here is the gist&lt;br /&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;http://gist.github.com/281093.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It returns true if an empty string is found. It really requires a knowledge of SQL, PostgreSQL&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.postgresql.org/docs/current/interactive/sql-createfunction.html&#34;&gt;CREATE FUNCTION&lt;/a&gt;, and Regular Expressions, to understand. Thanks to the wonderfully helpful PostgreSQL community with perfecting it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In order to use it to keep ASCII NULLS and fields that someone has just entered whitespace into you need to add it to your table as a constraint.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s an example create table gist using it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;http://gist.github.com/281118.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;br /&gt;remember it returns true on null&amp;rsquo;s and whitespace so you have to say NOT emtpy( field ).&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;br /&gt;
This &lt;span xmlns:dc=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/&#34; href=&#34;http://purl.org/dc/dcmitype/Text&#34; rel=&#34;dc:type&#34;&gt;work&lt;/span&gt; by &lt;a xmlns:cc=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/ns#&#34; href=&#34;http://www.xenoterracide.com&#34; property=&#34;cc:attributionName&#34; rel=&#34;cc:attributionURL&#34;&gt;Caleb Cushing&lt;/a&gt; is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>